Eloise Hubbard Linscott collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series II: Sound Recordings
  - SR170, circa 1940, 1 8-inch disc
    Performed by Langdon Ambrose (guitar, harmonica, and vocals), of Sandwich, New Hampshire. "Jackpot Joe" is Ambrose's own composition. Collection original ID: XXV.
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr170a
      - Put On Your Old Grey Bonnet
      - Cut Down the Old Pine Tree
      - Red Wing
      - Polly Wolly Doodle
      - Golden Slippers
      - Turkey in the Straw
      - Hold Me Honey
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr170b
      - Jackpot Joe
  - SR171, circa 1943-1953, 1 8-inch disc
    "Marching Through Georgia" performed by Dennis McClure (the caller), of Willimantic, Connecticut. Collection original ID: XXV.
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr171a
      - Larry O'Gaff
      - Banjo solo
      - Untitled
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr171b
      - Marching Through Georgia
      - Jennie Jenkins
  - SR172, September 28, 1946, 1 8-inch disc
    While the name "Doc Converse band" is written on the disc sleeve, the recording does not seem to be of the New Hampshire Guides Band. Maynard Reynolds and Sid Luther were recorded on this date, and William A. Adams is credited elsewhere in this collection as an autoharp player (SR130). An autoharp may be the instrument heard on Side B.
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr172a
      - Paul Stream
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr172b
      - The End of a Perfect Day
      - I Love You Truly
  - SR173, August 19, 1946, 1 8-inch disc
    Performed by L.C. (Pop) Brock.
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr173a
      - Old Pod-Auger Times
      - Old Pod-Auger Times (one verse)
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr173b
      - Old Pod-Auger Times
  - SR174, July 5, 1944, 1 8-inch disc
    "Bachelor Days" performed by Helen (who may be Linscott's sister, Helen) for Charlie (who may be Linscott's husband, Charles. Helen accompanies herself on piano. "I'm a Moron" performed as a duet with two unidentified people (one may be a child). Tunes on Side B may also be performed by Helen.
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr174a
      - Bachelor Days
      - I'm a Moron
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr174b
      - Sleighbells
      - Untitled
  - SR175, October 29, 1943, 1 6-inch disc
    Performed by Carrie B. Grover (fiddle and vocals), in Gorham, Maine. Collector's original ID: XI.
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr175a
      - For to Drive My Father's Cows
      - British Grenadiers
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr175b
      - Bagpipe tune
  - SR176, October 30, 1943, 1 6-inch disc
    Performed by Carrie B. Grover (fiddle), in Gorham, Maine. Collector's original ID: XVIII.
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr176a
      - Highland Fling [Lord Moira's Fling]
      - Catholic Boys
      - Miss McCleod's Reel
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr176b
      - Hull's Victory
      - Speed the Plow [Speed the Plough]
  - SR177, October 29, 1943, 1 6-inch disc
    Performed by Carrie B. Grover (vocals), in Gorham, Maine. Collector's original ID: XX.
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr177a
      - Plains of Waterloo
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr177b
      - Plains of Waterloo
  - SR178, October 29, 1943, 1 6-inch disc
    Performed by Carrie B. Grover (fiddle), in Gorham, Maine. Collector's original ID: IX.
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr178a
      - Money Musk [Monymusk]
      - Leather Britches [Leather Breeches; Lord McDonald's Reel]
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr178b
      - Dodge and Six
      - Kitty Kick-Up
  - SR179, October 29, 1943, 1 6-inch disc
    Performed by Carrie B. Grover (vocals), in Gorham, Maine. Collector's original ID: XIII.
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr179a
      - It Was On a Winter's Morning
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr179b
      - It Was On a Winter's Morning (continued)
  - SR180, October 29, 1943, 1 6-inch disc
    Performed by Carrie B. Grover (fiddle and vocals), in Gorham, Maine. Collector's original ID: XIX.
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr180a
      - Rakes of Kildare
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr180b
      - Johnny Bull Mind Your Eye
      - The Three Sons Jeffrey, James, and John
  - SR181, October 29, 1943, 1 6-inch disc
    Performed by Carrie B. Grover (fiddle), in Gorham, Maine. "Uncle Jim's tune" is a variant of "My Love She's But a Lassie Yet." Collector's original ID: XVI.
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr181a
      - Fiddle tune
      - Soldier's Joy
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr181b
      - Beaux of Oak Hill
      - Uncle Jim's Tune
  - SR182, October 29, 1943, 1 6-inch disc
    Performed by Carrie B. Grover (fiddle), in Gorham, Maine. Collector's original ID: XVII.
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr182a
      - Fiddle tune
      - Portland Fancy
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr182b
      - Casey Jones
      - Molly Braligan
  - SR183, March 8, 1947, 1 6-inch disc
    Program recorded for Leland Powers School, in Massachusetts. Recordings of male singers (possible Bourne Male Quartet and Chorus), accompanied by piano.
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr183a
      - Shenandoah
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr183b
      - Reuben Ranzo
  - SR184, August 18, 1948, 1 6 1/2-inch disc
    Performed by the Shaker Singers, of Enfield, New Hampshire. By the time of this recording the remainder of the community had relocated to Canterbury, New Hampshire, so it is uncertain where the recording was made. Collection original ID: I.
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr184a
      - More Love
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr184b
      - The Humble Heart
  - SR185, circa 1944-1949, 1 6-inch disc
    Side A: performer is an unidentified man; Linscott sings along with him towards the end. Side B: performer may be John Hubbard Linscott; introduced by Linscott.
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr185a
      - Etta Lee
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr185b
      - The Man I Love
  - SR186, October 29, 1943, 1 6-inch disc
    Performed by Carrie B. Grover (fiddle), in Gorham, Maine. Grover whistles only one tune (Side B, track 1). Collector's original ID: X.
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr186a
      - Hoodle But and Hoodle Ben
      - Pigtown Fling (variation)
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr186b
      - Whistling tune
      - Cuckoo's Nest
  - SR187, January 17, 1947, 1 6-inch disc
    Performed by Edson H. Cole (fiddle), in Freedom, New Hampshire. Piano accompaniment by an unidentifed person. Side B has no audible content.
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr187a
      - Jig
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr187b
      - Jig
  - SR188, January 4, 1949, 1 6-inch disc
    Performed by Llewellyn S. Powers (fiddle). Piano accompaniment by an unidentified person. Collector's original ID: VI (but crossed out).
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr188a
      - Cinderella Waltz
      - Going to Boston
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr188b
      - My Love Is But A Lassie Yet
      - Going to Boston (fragment)
  - SR189, December 29, 1945, 1 6-inch disc
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr189a
      - Smith's Reel
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr189b
      - Miss Sears' Reel
  - SR190, circa 1944, 1 6-inch disc
    Performed by Eloise Hubbard Linscott (piano and vocals). "Ele" (written on the sleeve) was Linscott's nickname.
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr190a
      - I'll Walk Alone
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr190b
      - Lili Marlene
  - SR191, 1 6 1/2-inch disc
    Performed by Happy Hale (caller). Audio is very low.
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr191a
      - Mrs. McLeod's Reel (?) (with calls)
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr191b
      - Mrs. McLeod's Reel (?) (with calls)
  - SR192, undated, 1 6 1/2-inch disc
    Performed by Happy Hale (caller). Audio is very low. Collector's original ID: II.
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr192a
      - Merry Widow (?) (with calls)
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr192b
      - Quadrille (with calls)
  - SR193, 1 6 1/2-inch disc
    - Side A: Music for the contra dance Lady Walpole's Reel (with calls), undated, afc1942002_sr193a
      - Untitled tune
    - Side B: Music for the dance Morning Star (with calls), afc1942002_sr193b
      - Haste to the Wedding [Come Haste to the Wedding]
  - SR194, undated, 1 6 1/2-inch disc
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr194a
      - Music for a circle dance: Untitled (fragment)
      - Music for the contra dance Lady Walpole's Reel (with calls): Untitled
    - Side B: Music for the dance Merry Widow (with calls) [Paul Jones], afc1942002_sr194b
      - Untitled tune
  - SR195, undated, 1 6 1/2-inch disc
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr195a
      - Nellie Gray (with calls)
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr195b
      - Nellie Gray (with calls)
  - SR196, circa 1942-1945, 1 6 1/2-inch disc
    Harry Philbrick (interviewee and vocals). John Hubbard Linscott (interviewer and vocals). Harry and John were friends.
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr196a
      - Interview with Harry Philbrick
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr196b
      - Interview with Harry Philbrick (continued)
      - Swing Low, Sweet Chariot (duet)
  - SR197, September 20, 1946 (Side A); September 21, 1946 (Side B), 1 6 1/2-inch disc
    Performers include Al Burns, Miles Cates, Bob Hocknell, and John Hubbard Linscott, in Boston, Massachusetts.
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr197a
      - Put Your Arms Around Me, Honey
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr197b
      - You Are My Sunshine
  - SR198, circa 1941-1951, 1 6 1/2-inch disc
    Performed by John Hubbard Linscott (clarinet).
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr198a
      - Untitled/Untitled
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr198b
      - Untitled/Untitled
  - SR199, circa 1946, 1 6 1/2-inch disc
    Side A: performed by Bob Hope (spoken word). Recorded from a radio broadcast.
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr199a
      - Radio broadcast, with Bob Hope
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr199b
      - Testing
  - SR200, May 26, 1946, 1 6 1/2-inch disc
    Performed by Herbert Meatty (fiddle). Piano accompaniment by an unidentified person.
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr200a
      - Hull's Victory
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr200b
      - Pop Goes the Weasel
  - SR201, May 26, 1946, 1 6 1/2-inch disc
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr201a
      - Devil's Dream
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr201b
      - Ricketts Hornpipe
  - SR202, May 26, 1946; September 28, 1946, 1 6 1/2-inch disc
    "Will the Weaver" performed by George Andrew (Stonewall) Jackson. All other tunes performed by Doc Converse (authoharp). Collector's original ID: II. Converse refers to the instrument as a "mountain piano."
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr202a
      - Will the Weaver (fragment) [Bill the Weaver; Willie Weaver]
      - I Love You Truly
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr202b
      - Just A-Wearying for You
  - SR203, September 28, 1946, 1 6 1/2-inch disc
    Performed by Maynard Reynolds (vocals), in Pittsburg, New Hampshire. Collector's original ID: I.
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr203a
      - Lumbermen's Lament
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr203b
      - Keyhole in the Door
  - SR204, September 28, 1946, 1 6-inch disc
    Performed by Doc Converse (authoharp). Converse refers to the instrument as a "mountain piano."
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr204a
      - The End of a Perfect Day
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr204b
      - I Love You Truly
  - SR205, 1 6-inch disc
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr205a
      - The End of a Perfect Day
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr205b
      - The End of a Perfect Day
  - SR206, September 28, 1946, 1 6 1/2-inch disc
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr206a
      - The End of a Perfect Day
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr206b
      - I Love You Truly
  - SR207, February 26, 1943, 1 6 1/2-inch disc
    Performed by Mrs. Crosby
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr207a
      - Charlie Is a Dandy
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr207b
      - Sleighing With the Girls
  - SR208, November 5, 1942 or January 1, 1943, 1 6 1/2-inch disc
    Performed by Will E. Ayer, of Fitchburg, Massachusetts. The names "Crosby" and "Miss Sherman" appear on the disc label and sleeve respectively, but are not heard on this either disc side.
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr208a
      - A Wet Sheet and a Flowing Sea
      - Yankee Volunteer
      - Battle of Lake Champlain
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr208b
      - Battle of Lake Erie [Perry's Battle on Lake Erie]
  - SR209, August 6, 1940, 1 10-inch disc
    Performed by Sam Young, Jr. Collector's original ID: D.
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr209a
      - Lass of Mohea [Little Mohea]
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr209b
      - Patrick Sheenian
      - Thanksgiving Morn
      - Drowsy Sleeper [Who's That At My Bedroom Window]
  - SR210, November 9, 1941, 1 10-inch disc
    H. Rae (Mrs. Herbert D.) Farnham, in Swanville, Maine. Audio on both sides is low, and recorded at the wrong speed.
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr210a
      - Frog in the Well [Frog He Would A-wooing Go]
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr210b
      - Turkish Shore
  - SR211, November 11, 1941, 1 10-inch disc
    Performed by George Andrew (Stonewall) Jackson, in Manchester, New Hampshire.
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr211a
      - Shanty Boys
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr211b
      - Cutting Down the Pine
  - SR212, April 20, 1943, 1 10-inch disc
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr212a
      - In the Good Old State of Maine
      - Jack Haggerty
      - Sandy Stream
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr212b
      - Sandy Stream (continued)
      - Zealand Song
  - SR213, May 26, 1946, 1 10-inch disc
    Performed by George Andrew (Stonewall) Jackson, in Manchester, New Hampshire. Collector's original ID: II.
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr213a
      - Bum from Omaha
      - Hills of Glanshee
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr213b
      - Lass of Mohea [Little Mohea]
  - SR214, September 26, 1946 (Side B), 1 10-inch disc
    Performed by Charles W. (Charlie) Porter, in Lancaster, New Hampshire. Collector's original ID: XI.
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr214a
      - Boston Burglar
      - Lass of Mohea [Little Mohea]
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr214b
      - Lass of Mohea [Little Mohea]
  - SR215, May 26, 1946, 1 10-inch disc
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr215a
      - Wild Irish Paddy
      - Will the Weaver [Bill the Weaver; "Willie Weaver]
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr215b
      - Duck Foot Sue (fragment)
      - Duck Foot Sue
      - Maid of the Mountain Brow
  - SR216, January 17, 1947 (Side B), 1 10-inch disc
    Performed by Edson H. Cole, in Freedom, New Hampshire. Some speed errors from the original recording process are evident.
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr216a
      - Old Zip Coon
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr216b
      - Old Waltz
  - SR217, November 16, 1941 (Side A); March 9, 1943 (Side B), 1 10-inch disc
    Performers include George (Rocky Mountain George) Brown, Mable Johnson Hunter (guitar and vocals), and Eloise Hubbard Linscott (piano). Some speed errors from the original recording process are evident.
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr217a
      - Good and Jolly Fisher Man [My True Love was a Fisherman]
      - State of Arkansas
      - Red River Valley
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr217b
      - Margaret Gray
      - Red River Valley
      - My Old New Hampshire Home
      - Margaret Gray
  - SR218, July 31, 1946, 1 10-inch disc
    Performed by Harry A. Simpson. Side A: Towards the end, an unidentified female voice joins Simpson.
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr218a
      - My Old New Hampshire Home
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr218b
      - Broken Home
  - SR219, September 28, 1946, 1 10-inch disc
    Performed by Harvey (Doc) Converse. Collector's original ID: I.
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr219a
      - Drive On Paul Stream
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr219b
      - Willy Hawes Two-Step
      - Pipe Dreams
      - Holy Night [Silent Night]
  - SR220, September 25, 1946, 1 10-inch disc
    Performed by Charles W. (Charlie) Porter. Two locations are noted on the disc sleeve: Stark, New Hampshire, and Lancaster. It is not clear if one of these towns is where Porter lived, or where the recording was made. Collector's original ID: I.
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr220a
      - Joiner Dick
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr220b
      - Kissing Bony Sally by the Light of the Moon
  - SR221, September 27, 1946, 1 10-inch disc
    Performed by Maynard Reynolds, in Pittsburg, New Hampshire. Collector's original ID: II.
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr221a
      - Etta Lee
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr221b
      - Italian Girl I Loved So Well
  - SR222, April 20, 1943, 1 10-inch disc
    Performed by George Andrew (Stonewall) Jackson, in Manchester, New Hampshire. Collector's original ID: 1.
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr222a
      - Hills of Glanshee
      - Bull Dog Song
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr222b
      - Hills of Glanshee
      - Dan Day
  - SR223, October 28, 1945, 1 10-inch disc
    Performed by Arthur W. Hanson (fiddle), in Ossipee, New Hampshire. Collector’s original ID: IV.
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr223a
      - Portland Fancy
      - Untitled Waltz
      - McDonnell's Reel
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr223b
      - Peeler's Jacket Reel
      - Varsovienne
      - Rochester Schottische [Rochester Five-Step Schottische]
  - SR224, October 28, 1945, 1 10-inch disc
    Performed by Arthur W. Hanson (fiddle), in Ossipee, New Hampshire.
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr224a
      - Lil Judy's Reel [Little Judy's Reel]
      - St. Anne's Reel
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr224b
      - Paddy on the Railroad
      - Waltz
  - SR225, November 8, 1941, 1 10-inch disc
    Performed by Frank Cates (fiddle), in Rockland, Maine. Collector’s original ID: I.
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr225a
      - Brown's Reel (Paddy on the Turnpike)
      - Clog (Harvest Home Hornpipe)
      - Speed the Plow [Speed the Plough]
      - Portland Fancy
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr225b
      - Version of Douglas' Favorite (Mountain Hornpipe)
      - Soldier's Joy
      - Tuning
      - Quadrille
  - SR226, November 8, 1941 (Side A); November 8, 1941 (Side B, song 1); November 9, 1941 (Side B, songs 2 through 4), 1 10-inch disc
    Side A: performed by Frank Cates (fiddle). Side B, tune 1: performed by Frank Cates (fiddle). Side B, tunes 2 through 4: performed by Herbert D. (Bert) Farnham (fiddle). Frank Cates recorded in Rockland, Maine. Herbert D. (Bert) Farnham recorded in Swanville, Maine. Collector’s original ID: III.
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr226a
      - Devil's Dream
      - Arkansas Traveler
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr226b
      - Portland Fancy
      - Come Under My Plaidie (The Black Rogue) [Come Under My Pladdie]
      - Flowers of Edinburgh/Polka
  - SR227, April 12, 1940, 1 10-inch disc
    Recorded at Dedham Country Day School, in Dedham, Massachusetts. Piano accompaniment is probably by Linscott. All songs but "Captain Kidd" sung by the students. "Captain Kidd" may performed by John Hubbard Linscott. Collector’s original ID: II
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr227a
      - Haul the Bowline [Haul Away the Bowline]
      - Rio Grande [Ryo Grande]
      - Billy Boy
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr227b
      - Captain Kidd
      - Jolly Old Roger
  - SR228, circa 1943-1953, 1 10-inch disc
    Side A: Edson H. Cole (fiddle and vocals), in Freedom, New Hampshire. The audio is very low, and the speed is too fast. Side B: High school quartette (all male voices), in Freedom, New Hampshire
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr228a
      - Lanciers (with calls) [Lanciers Quadrille]
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr227b
      - The Jolly Blacksmith's Lay
      - Let Us All Unite in Love
  - SR229, September 8, 1940, 1 10-inch disc
    Performed by Joe (Buddy) Edwards. Collector’s original ID: III.
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr229a
      - Cecelia
      - Go In and Out the Window
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr229b
      - Merry Oldsmobile [In My Merry Oldsmobile]
      - Whiskey Johnny [Whisky Johnny]
      - Let Me Call You Sweetheart
  - SR230, September 1, 1940, 1 10-inch disc
    Performed by GHR (vocals) and Everett Davey (guitar). GHR may be George H. Reed. Collector’s original ID: II.
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr230a
      - Canaday I-O
      - Tittery Nan
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr230b
      - Billy Boy
      - Tommy's Gone to Hilo
      - Johnny Boker
      - Whisky Johnny
  - SR231, June 3, 1949, 1 10-inch disc
    Performed by the Bourne Male Quartet and Chorus
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr231a
      - Rio Grande
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr231b
      - Homeward Bound
  - SR232, January 9, 1944 or 1947, 1 10-inch disc
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr232a
      - Paddy Get Back
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr232b
      - Doggerel
  - SR233, undated, 1 10-inch disc
    Performed by William J. (Jack) Sherrard. Collector's original ID: II (Side A); III (Side B)
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr233a
      - Bunco Kelly and Twenty-Four Able Seamen
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr233b
      - Bunco Kelly and Twenty-Four Able Seamen (continued): his business; jail term; his book on the State Penitentiary
  - SR234, October 4, 1947, 1 10-inch disc
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr234a
      - Mystery of the Mary Celeste
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr234b
      - Bunco Kelly and the Wooden Indian
  - SR235, April 24, 1948, 1 10-inch disc
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr235a
      - Tacks and Sheets
      - Haul the Bowline
      - Johnny Boker
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr235b
      - Leave Her Johnny (Time for All of Us to Leave Her)
  - SR236, undated, 1 10-inch disc
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr236a
      - The Dreadnaught
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr236b
      - Paddy Get Back
  - SR237, September 29, 1945 (Side A); April 6, 1946 (Side B), 1 10-inch disc
    Performed by William J. (Jack) Sherrard. Collector’s original ID: VI.
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr237a
      - Hoisting the Main t'g'ntsail
      - Hawaiian Isles
      - A Long Time Ago
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr237b
      - A Long Time Ago
  - SR238, September 29, 1945, 1 10-inch disc
    Performed by William J. (Jack) Sherrard. Collector’s original ID: IV.
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr238a
      - Sailing of The Port Jackson
      - Homeward Bound
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr238b
      - Hoisting the Main T'gal't's'l
      - A Long Time Ago (Limejuicer Version)
  - SR239, January 8, 1944 (Side A); April 15, 1944 (Side B), 1 10-inch disc
    Performed by William J. (Jack) Sherrard. Collector’s original ID: III.
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr239a
      - Johnny's Gone to Hilo
      - Banks of the Sacramento
      - A Long Time Ago
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr239b
      - Hoisting the Maintgs'l
  - SR240, March 17, 1946, 1 10-inch disc
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr240a
      - Rio Grande
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr240b
      - The Dreadnaught (fragment)
  - SR241, January 20, 1947, 1 10-inch disc
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr241a
      - The Western Ocean
      - Untitled
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr241b
      - The Western Ocean
      - Untitled
  - SR242, February 3, 1947 (Side B), 1 10-inch disc
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr242a
      - Sally Brown
      - Sally Brown
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr242b
      - Golden Vanity
  - SR243, March 17, 1946, 1 10-inch disc
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr243a
      - The Dreadnaught
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr243b
      - Roll the Cotton Down
  - SR244, April 24, 1948 (Side A); April 1948 (Side B), 1 10-inch disc
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr244a
      - Johnny's Gone to Hilo
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr244b
      - A Long Time Ago (USA version)
  - SR245, April 1948 (Side A); April 24, 1948 (Side B), 1 10-inch disc
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr245a
      - How Jack Went to Sea
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr245b
      - 10,000 Miles Away
  - SR246, September 28, 1943 (Side A); 1943 (Side B), 1 10-inch disc
    Performed by William J. (Jack) Sherrard. Collector’s original ID: I.
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr246a
      - Johnny's Gone to Hilo
      - Homeward Bound
      - Unidentified ditty
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr246b
      - Renzo
      - Haul the Bowline
      - Roll the Cotton Down
      - Whisky Johnny
  - SR247, October 4, 1947, 1 10-inch disc
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr247a
      - Across The Western Ocean
    - Side B:, afc1942002_sr247b
      - Blow the Man Down
  - SR248, June 3, 1949, 1 10-inch disc
    Performed by the Bourne Male Quartet and Chorus; William J. (Jack) Sherrard, soloist. Side B is blank.
    - Side A:, afc1942002_sr248a